DANIEL SIXSMITH

61 evergreen Grove, Forrestfield - 0435251774 - D.O.B 15/01/1999 Dancore99@outlook.com · www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-sixsmith

Full-stack qualified with a passion for software and application design, ready to build systems for a great user experience and practicality. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Western Australia through their Coding Bootcamp, with newly developed skills in Html, native css and bootstrap framework, vanilla javascript with a good understanding of jquery and node.js. With strong problem solving skills I can optimize design and implantation of user-face products. With each project, my aim is to best engage my audience while also working closely with my team to create productive and user-friendly experience. I applied aspects of my skill set in my recent project that used two api's which collected data on video game deals.

EXPERIENCE

NOV 2014 - JULY 2017

BARISTA, MUNDARING ARTISAN BAKERY

Working at the bakery in Mundaring was a great place to learn about how to communicate with people as well as how to manage a fast paced environment Some of my responsibilities in my role at the bakery were;

- Communication with patrons and vendors
- To train new staff in all areas of the business
- Support the management team in an IT technical support that was required

JULY 2017 - PRESENT

CONCRETE AND STONE FINISHED, SHINEIT SYSTEMS

Over my time at ShineIT systems I have had the opportunity to learn new skills and then refine those skills. It has allowed me to grow and although I am now ready to move on and learn new skills my time with the business has been incredibly educational.

Some of the skills that I have refined over my time are;

- Machine operator \circ This is a large part of my work. I used many different types of machines such as 650kg floor Grinds, heavy duty edge grinders, drills, multi-tools and auto scrubbers.
- Scheduling o I assisted with organizing job sheets as well as scheduling employees to those works
- Organisation and preparation of equipment

 The Organisation and preparation of equipment is incredibly important to ensure that they were no delays in beginning the work. It is my responsibility to ensure that Ute is packed every morning with all tooling/machinery required for the job and then that those tools/machines are cleaned and packed away properly at the end of the shift
- Book keeping \circ This was a skill that I was able to pick up over my time in the business. My employer required assistance in the management of their book keeping and I was able to assist. The business uses the Xero accounting software. After some time I was then able to train other employees in using this software.
- Quoting O I am able to assist the business by completing quoting both in the office and onsite when required. I speak to clients about what they are looking for and then have the ability to provide them with a quote that both the business and the client were happy with.
- Communication with clients to ensure future work As a small business we did not use commercial advertisement and therefore that way they were able to ensure we had constant work. This therefore was through word of mouth. Over time I was able to learn different techniques while speaking to clients to ensure that should they need our service again or someone they know, we would be their first call.
- Test & Tagging O In my time in the company if became apparent that somewhere we were
 losing money was on the cost of test and tagging out equipment. I decided to put myself
 through the test and tag course and buy the required machinery. This then became my
 responsibility for the business. I also began providing this service for other small businesses in
 the area where possible.

OHS management

• This was something that I decided to take on myself in the business. I feel strongly that all business should have strong OSH policy and that we should always be striving to make sure that we are working as safely as possible on all sites that we attend. I also ensure that all of our equipment was in working order and always up to Australian Standards.

APRIL 2019 – AUGUST 2019, APRIL 2020 – AUGUST 2020

WABL GAMES CONTROLLER, BASKETBALL WA & HILLS RAIDERS BASKETBALL ASSOCIATION

WABL Games Controller has been a recent venture, a path that lead to me learning new skills in leadership and interpersonal skills. I feel passionately about being an active part of the community and this position has allowed me to do this. These skills include;

- Staff Allocation \circ This was a large part of my job, I was to make sure that each court and time slot had enough referees, first aiders and official scorers.
- Training of team members o This role become very important early on in my time in Hills Raiders as a new electronic score board was installed. Every game I explained how to use this system. I also made sure during the game that I was always available.
- Diffusion of Tension O WABL (Western Australian Basketball League) is the next step from domestic competition. For players, coaches and spectators, these games can get very intense which can lead to high tensing between officials and patrons. A part of my role I was able to defuse all situations tension to ensure that there was a fair solution.
- Arena management O For a basketball association to have a team in the league we
 must first have an arena. After 10 years The Mundaring Shire built us a state of the art
 stadium. As my job description requires, I open, organize, staff and manage a multimillion dollar stadium.

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2016

COMPLETION OF YEAR 12, EASTERN HILLS SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL

During my years at eastern hills, I completed all classes to a high standard. When graduating, I was given 2 excellence awards, 1 Merit award, 1 recognition award and 1 achievement award, these are listed below.

Year 11 awards

- Certificate of Excellence, Academic Medal in Computing
- Certificate of Achievement, Top Student Applied Information Technology
- Certificate of Recognition, Most Outstanding Qualities of Citizenship Both Within the School and Wider Community.
- Edith Cowan University, Citizenship Award

Year 12 awards

- Letter of appreciation for working in the position of Head Boy
- Certificate of Excellence, **Vocational & Education Achievement Medal**
- Certificate of Excellence, Academic Medal For Business and Computing
- Certificate of Recognition, Personal Excellence VET Award
- Certificate of Merit, Outstanding Achievement in Computing Five Vocational & Education Training Certificates
- Certificate of Achievement, Top Student Applied Information Technology

Certificate of Graduation, Completion of Year 12

NOVEMBER 2015

CERT III, NORTH METRO TAFE

Cert 11 In Information, Digital media and technology

NOVEMBER 2016

CERT IV, NORTH METRO TAFE

Cert IV in Information technology networking

JANUARY 2022

Full Stack Developer, UWA, Trilogy

Full stack developer

SKILLS

- Communication
 - This is a skill I learnt many years ago.
 Commination in my opinion is a key skill in any business especially in when it comes to learning a new set of skills
- Efficiency
 - Efficiently is a key player in any industry, it is a fine line between working fast and getting the job done properly.
- Works well with a team and by myself
 - Over the past few years I have been

- · Handles well under pressure
 - My most recent jobs at Hills Raiders and ShineIT taught me this skill, understanding how to handle high pressure systems always helps yourself as well as you colleges
- Willing to go the extra mile to get the job done
 - I am enthusiastic and always ready to learn something new
- Strong Work Ethic
 - I take pride in any and all talks I complete.

ACTIVITIES

OCTOBER 2015 - PRESENT

VALUNTEER COMMITTEE MEMBER, HILLS RAIDERS BASKETBALL ASSOCIATION

As a Volunteer committee member my job is to support the committee in making decisions to better the association and the people in it. over the years I spent time organizing equipment for the property officer, I played large part in bringing Hills Raiders into the technological age. Changing paper scoring in to IPad based scoring, installing and training parents and staff on a state of the art LED scoreboard. I am currently in an executive committee position which involves the handling of personal information, setting up game days for the coming season, on the night support of equipment and tech support.

REFERENCES

HILLS RAIDERS BASKETBALL ASSOSSIATION DOMESTIC

Administrator – Shannan Jones

Mobile: 0447971526

Email: admin@hillsraiders.com.au

SHINE-IT SYSTEMS

Supervisor - Scott Dunstan Mobile: 0437350741

PERSONAL REFERENCES

Casey Twiname

Mobile: 0488991275

Deb White-Keily Mobile: 0417174644